# Sam Gorick

Chicago, Illinois, 60654 | 312-539-9842 | samgorick.sq@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Fullstack developer experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with six years of experience in Product in Financial Services. I possess strong skills in stakeholder management, product management and strategy to help companies drive customer-focussed outcomes that result in commercial success. Certified in SCRUM and PRINCE2.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, React Native, Redux, HTML, CSS, SCRUM, PRINCE2, Project Management

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Budget Better - Demo | Github Frontend | Github Backend

Mobile budgeting app to help users take control of their spending and saving

- Combined React Native and Native-Base components to create User Interface
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to store encrypted user information client-side with AsyncStorage
- Synthesized and manipulated financial data, using Victory Chart to visualize simple graphs throughout the app
- Introduced Redux for state management throughout the application
- Built Ruby on Rails API backend with MVC pattern and a Postgres database

# Play With Words - Demo | Github Frontend | Github Backend

Fun word game where a user is scored based on the words they find in a set of letters, with ability to challenge others

- Implemented vanilla Javascript/CSS/HTML frontend to ensure full customization of game features and visuals
- Initiated Ruby on Rails API backend with MVC pattern and a PostgreSQL database
- Validated user guesses with frontend Regex dictionary, plus further validation on letters used
- Used Javascript to manipulate CSS classes to make letters visually change as selected by user
- Added animations and sounds to make the game more interactive, both visually and audibly

## Record It - Demo | Github Frontend | Github Backend

Social networking app to write and tag notes, accept/decline follow requests and see a consolidated activity feed

- Designed 'follow' functionality with ability to search for users, request to follow and see followers
- Integrated Formik and Yup for form management and validation, Moment JS library for time parsing
- Developed persistent log-in with LocalStorage

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Barclays Bank PLC**

Cambridge University

London, UK

Senior Product Manager - Head of Pricing Strategy - Business Checking Accounts

11/2018 - 03/2020

- Built SQL center of excellence across Product from scratch, enabling data-led product management
- Developed innovative pricing strategy to retain market share ahead of the competition
- Delivered pricing changes across 1M accounts, resulting in an £8M income increase
- Managed legal, regulatory and technological changes for successful implementation
- Managed performance for two employees as well as leading on recruitment across Product

# Senior Propositions Manager - Product Owner for SmartBusiness Dashboard

06/2015 - 10/2018

- Increased user base to 30,000 customers from launch, utilizing digital content marketing
- Built a brand new mobile experience and increased customer eligibility by 25%
- Delivered an innovative new user set-up journey which resulted in a 90% uplift in product engagement on first login
- Managed offshore supplier to define roadmap and deliver 40 successful releases in 21 months using SCRUM
- Delivered IBISWorld to ~2,000 front-office colleagues, building the product and leading implementation
- IBISWorld now has 400+ logins per week and is one of the most successful colleague tools ever launched

### Future Leaders Development Program, Generalist

09/2013 - 06/2015

Selected to participate in a challenging training program designed to provide accelerated learning and fast-track talented individuals into leadership roles. Received technical and soft skills training through four rotations, in Personal Banking Strategy, Digital Marketing, Program Management and Credit Card Strategy

## **EDUCATION**

**Flatiron School** 

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

03/2020 - 07/2020

Chicago, IL

Cambridge, UK

Theology and Religious Studies Master of Arts (Cantab)

09/2010 - 07/2013